ERIC SAI KIT CHEUNG

SOFTWARE ENGINEER | FULL STACK DEVELOPER

PROFILE

I've owned and operated a food business in Hawaii & Brooklyn, self-published a fiction novel, and am now a Full-stack Software Engineer specializing in React & Redux, JavaScript, and Ruby & Rails.

I love to build aesthetically pleasing projects, find creative solutions to problems, and am an avid food adventurer and cat instagram follower.

EDUCATION

FLATIRON SCHOOL FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT

FEBRUARY 2020 - JUNE 2020

Full Stack Web Development - React & Redux, JavaScript, Ruby & Rails, SQL and PostgreSQL

SOKA UNIVERSITY OF AMERICA BACHELOR OF ARTS

AUGUST 2008 - MAY 2012

Social Behavioral Sciences - 3.8 GPA

CONTACT



Eric.Saikit.Cheung@gmail.com



646.637.1808



https://ericskcheung.com



www.linkedin.com/in/eric-sk-cheung



erock_esquire

EXPERIENCE

HIES INC • FRONT-END DEVELOPER • JULY 2020 – AUGUST 2020

- Designed & rebuilt HIES company website using React & SASS.
- Incorporated PIXI.js to create realistic water effect on hero image.
- Redesigned with higher resolution HIES company logo, hero image, and page images using Adobe Photoshop & Illustrator.
- Original website pages reorganized & trimmed to strictly include vital text relevant to company's brand & services. Utilized React Router to preserve page URL addresses.

CURBALERT • FULL STACK DEVELOPER • JUNE 2020

React & Ruby Rails with PostgreSQL web app allowing users to post images & details of unwanted items on street onto a public map.

- Engineered codebase synchronizing Geolocation & Google Geocode API to translate latitude/longitude coordinates into addresses. Incorporated Google Directions API by decoding address polylines and accessing response keys to be plotted on map provided by Leaflet API.
- Collaborated functionality between AWS S3 Cloud & Rails Active Storage to store user post images on cloud bucket through Rails back-end API.

HANGOUTS • FULL STACK DEVELOPER • MAY 2020

React & Ruby Rails with PostgreSQL web app allowing users to plan meetups at location calculated to be equal distance between all participants

• Architected a Rails back-end call to YELP Search API to provide restaurant suggestions at user requested coordinates, and returned response data to be visually displayed on map provided by Leaflet API on front-end.

SUPER PETS • FULL STACK DEVELOPER • APRIL 2020

JavaScript & Ruby Rails with PostgreSQL web game.

- Implemented battle animations, sound effects, and background music using a combination of JavaScript functions working harmoniously with CSS.
- Coded web audio player allowing user to play multiple tracks during battle with pause, play, and skip with JavaScript class utilizing JavaScript's Audio Constructor.

BANZAI PHRESH • OWNER/SOLE PROPRIETOR • APRIL 2016 – JUNE 2018

Honolulu, HI

• Managed and operated a 6-month pop-up restaurant in Ala Moana Mall, Hawaii. Oversaw restaurant design, customer service, cooking, financials, and logistical operation of the business. We averaged 100 customers a day, maintained a 30% profit margin, with 4.5 star reviews on Yelp.

Brooklyn, NY

• Managed and operated an outdoor food booth for two seasons at Smorgasburg Market, Brooklyn. Oversaw restaurant design, customer service, cooking, financials, and logistical operation of the business. We averaged 200 customers a day and maintained a 25% profit margin.